

#### CONTACT ME AT

- 61 Matutum St. Brgy. St. Peter, Quezon City
- rheyannmagcalas@gmail.com
- https://rheyannmagcalas.github.io/
- +639159438825

#### SKILLS:

# Programming Languages and Frameworks:

- Python: Django, Flask
- PHP: CodeIgniter, Laravel
- JS: Javascript, Jquery
- Java, Groovy

#### Databases:

- SQL, MySQL
- Elasticsearch
- Redis
- Riak
- Hive, Impala
- MongoDB

#### ETL Tools:

- Streamsets
- Airflow
- Prefect
- Dask

## **Version Control:**

- Git
- Perforce
- SVN Tortoise

#### Provisioning:

- Vagrant
- Docker
- Ansible

# Message Queue:

- Rabbitmq
- Kafka
- Celery

# **RHEY ANN MAGCALAS**

#### WEB DEVELOPER AND DATA ENGINEER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

"I am a skilled-IT professional who exhibits expertise in building web application to simplify tasks and data analysis. I am passionate in everything I do and always give my 100%. When I undertake a project,I would go the extra mile and make it better than expected."

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Operation Software Tools Developer

July 2018 - present

Ringcentral - Shaw Blvd, Mandaluyong, Metro Manila, Philippines

#### As a Data Engineer:

- Manage all data pipelines, data architecture and data consistency/quality/reliability.
- Research new and emerging technology to improve data reliability, efficiency and quality and improve the current architecture
- Automation of deployment, configuration, alarming and visualization
- Data modeling, mining, production and explore and examine data to find hidden patterns
- Use sophisticated analytics programs, machine learning and statistical methods to to prepare data for use in predictive modeling.

#### As a Web Developer:

- Build, maintain and update tools which may be standalone or webenabled.
- Conduct planning, development, test and implementation of software request from the client.
- Monitoring and Support for the Existing Sites.
- Participate in on-call activity to prevent service interruption.

#### Mentor (Remote)

July 2019 - Present

Code Institute - Blackrock Business Park, Carysfort Ave, Blackrock, Co. Dublin, Ireland

 Provide guidance and advice to students on their journey to web development

#### **EDUCATIONAL HISTORY**

- JUNE 2010 MAY 2014
   Bachelor Of Science In
   Information Technology
   Polytechnic University of the
   Philippines, Sta.Mesa, Manila
- JUNE 2006 MARCH 2010
   Polytechnic University of the
   Philippines Laboratory High School,
   Sta.Mesa, Manila
- JUNE 2000 APRIL 2006
   P. Burgos Elementary School
   Altura St.Sta. Mesa, Manila

# TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Information Technology Infrastracture Library (ITIL) Training and Certification
- Basic Machine Learning Bootcamp
- Basic Python
- Effective Workplace Writing
- Empowerment of the Black-Belt Team
- Problem Solving Workshop
- Project Management 101

## AWARDS RECEIVED

- WRS Employee of the Quarter, 1H 2016
- WRS Employee of the Quarter, 1H 2017
- Top Performer Q2 2019

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Software Engineer

Feb 2018-Jun 2018

Truelogic - Makati City, Philippines

- System support and development of existing applications.
- Development of change request and enhancement requested by clients

## **Solution Efficiency Engineer**

March 2015-Jan 2018

Trend Micro - Ortigas Ave., Pasig City, Philippines

- Build, maintain and update tools which may be standalone or web-enabled.
- Conduct development, test and implementation of software following functional requirement and technical design documents.
- Conduct testing and monitoring of automated systems.
- Research new and emerging technology to improve technical skills.

#### Web Developer

Feb 2014-March 2015

Prople Inc. – Pioneer St., Mandaluyong City, Philippines

- System support and development of existing application
- Development of change request and enhancement requested by clients

#### Web Developer - Trainee

Nov 2013-Feb 2014

Prople Inc. – Pioneer St., Mandaluyong City, Philippines

 Working alongside the senior web developer to deliver optimum performance of clients' websites